{"questions":[{"category":"Personal Finance","question":"When an employee has money deducted from his paycheck to deposit into his employer’s retirement plan, the employee is contributing to his","choices":["1. 401(k) plan.","2. investment portfolio.","3. insurance plan.","4. savings account."],"correctAnswer":0,"questionHint":"its related with retirement","rationale":"This employee is making contributions to a 401(k) retirement plan. In this type of plan, the employer may match the employee’s contributions up to a limit that is set by the employer. Employees can choose not to contribute. If they do not contribute, they lose the employer’s contribution","difficultyLevel":"M"},{"category":"Personal Finance","question":"An important consideration when deciding how to invest money being saved for emergencies is the","choices":["1. dividends being charged. ","2. degree of liquidity.","3. limit on withdrawals.","4. higher potential return."],"correctAnswer":1,"questionHint":"cash availability and liquidity","rationale":"An emergency savings account needs to be easily converted to cash (liquid). Bank savings accounts are typically very liquid and safe because they are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC).","difficultyLevel":"E"},{"category":"Finance planing","question":"Which guideline is important to follow for successful budgeting?","choices":["1. Get a copy of the person’s three credit reports each year.","2. Know the location of the banks where accounts are held.","3. Have expenses that are not greater than income.","4. Earn a degree from a post-secondary education institution."],"correctAnswer":2,"questionHint":"related with expense and income","rationale":"The most important guideline to follow is to have a budget that has monthly expenses that do not exceed monthly income.","difficultyLevel":"E"},{"category":"Personal Finance","question":"Which tax is the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) responsible for collecting?","choices":["1. Sales tax.","2. City tax.","3. Federal income tax.","4. Property tax."],"correctAnswer":2,"questionHint":"related with income","rationale":"The IRS, an agency of the U.S. government, is responsible for collecting federal income taxes from people who earn income.","difficultyLevel":"M"},{"category":"Business Class","question":"An individual does NOT want to pay federal income tax on investment earnings. Therefore it is advisable for this person to buy","choices":["1. corporate bonds.","2. growth stocks.","3. stock mutual funds.","4. municipal bonds."],"correctAnswer":3,"questionHint":"related with bonds","rationale":"The interest earned on municipal bonds is tax-free (although a person may have some taxes, depending on the type of municipal bond).The income received from dividends on stocks and mutual funds is taxable income. The interest earned on savings accounts is taxable income.","difficultyLevel":"D"},{"category":"Business Class","question":"If a business corporation wants to raise capital but NOT create debt, it can","choices":["1. issue a bond.","2. issue common stock.","3. borrow money from a commercial bank.","4. borrow money from the government."],"correctAnswer":1,"rationale":" A corporation raises capital (money) when it issues stock, a share in the ownership of the company. Issuing stock does not create a debt. Issuing bonds or borrowing \r\nmoney from a financial institution or the government does create debt for the company.","difficultyLevel":"M"},{"category":"Business Class","question":"The advantage of mutual funds is that they are","choices":["1. an investment portfolio managed by the investor.","2. an investment that holds a wide range of different investments instruments, providing diversification.","3. usually less risky than investing in a savings account.","4. guaranteed to increase in value."],"correctAnswer":1,"rationale":"A mutual fund’s investment portfolio typically holds between 100 and 200 different types of investment instruments, including, for example, stocks, bonds, and money \r\nmarket securities. This diversification minimizes the investor’s risk. A mutual fund’s portfolio is managed by a professional fund manager which may be advantageous to \r\nan inexperienced investor. They are not guaranteed to increase in value.","difficultyLevel":"E"},{"category":"Business Class","question":"A woman wants to buy an investment that will pay a fixed dividend, providing a source of steady retirement income. Which investment product best meets her needs?","choices":["1. Preferred stock.","2. Speculative stock.","3. Common stock.","4. Capital growth stock."],"correctAnswer":0,"rationale":"Preferred stock is issued with a fixed dividend per share. The regular dividend payments appeal to retired investors and others who desire a reliable stream of \r\nincome.","difficultyLevel":"D"},{"category":"Business Class","question":"A person sold her stock in ABC Company for a higher price per share than she bought it for. Therefore, she had a capital","choices":["1. gain.","2. loss.","3. surplus.","4. dividend."],"correctAnswer":0,"rationale":"If a person sells stock for a higher price per share than she bought it for, she has made a profit which is called a capital gain. If the person sells it for less \r\nthan she bought it for, she has a capital loss. Sale price – purchase price = capital gain or loss.","difficultyLevel":"E"},{"category":"Academy of Finance","question":"How does the degree of risk, that the insurance company has to take, influence the cost of the insurance policy?","choices":["1. The lower the risk, the higher the cost of the insurance premium.","2. The higher the risk, the higher the cost of the insurance premium.","3. The higher the risk, the lower the cost of the insurance premium.","4. There is no relationship between the risk and the cost of the insurance premium."],"correctAnswer":1,"rationale":"The higher the risk for the insurance company, the higher the cost of the premium for the insurance policy.","difficultyLevel":"M"}]}